DANIEL HAGOS

Full Stack Developer with over 3 years of experience in designing, developing, and maintaining web applications for Ministry of Local Government Eritrea and health care companies find best solutions and delivering amazing experiences and software.

SKILLS

- Frontend development: DHTML, HTML, XML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Angular, React, Redux
- Database management: SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, fire store
- CMS Tools: WordPress, Joomla, WIX
- **DevOps:** Docker, Firebase

- Backend development: Java, Go, Node, PHP(basic foundation), ASP.NET, jQuery
- Version control and Build Tools: Git, Jenkins, GitHub, Web Pack, Babel, NPM/Yarn
- Conferencing platforms: MS Teams, WebEx, Zoom, Skype, Slack, Confluence
- Others: API, SharePoint, Web service design

WORK HISTORY

Full Stack Web Developer, 07/2020 - 10/2023

Eri-Tech – Kampala Uganda

- Developed web services and APIs that enabled seamless communication between front-end and back-end components, enhancing application functionality
- Used React JS as front end mixed with Styled component which is powerful CSS and JS frame work,
 CSS frame works of Bootstrap and tailwind as front end and Node. JS as backend with MySQL as database.
- Worked with back-end development team to deliver full solutions to clients resulting in 15% increase in client satisfaction.
- Contributing to 40% increase in project delivery speed and 30% reduction in development costs through efficient coding practices and reusable components.

Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JS, React, Node, Styled-Components, MySQL, Go, Jest

Android App Developer, 09/2018 - 05/2019

Milano Dev – Kampala, Uganda

• Developed and maintained the "Home Doctors" Android application using Java and Gradle, facilitating

patient-doctor appointments and self-medication guidance with a team of 4 full stack developers.

- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams using tools like Jira and Slack to gather requirements, design solutions, and deliver high-quality software that met user needs and exceeded business objectives.
- Improved the application which resulted in reduced clerk appointment scheduling by 70%
- Technologies Used: Android Studio, IntelliJ IDEA, Android, Java, SDK, Git, Gradle

Java Full Stack Programmer, 08/2016 - 09/2018

Ministry Of Local Government – Mendefera, Eritrea

- PIMS (Practice management software)
- Developed Human Resource Software, helps HR members recruit staff, take attendance, track individual staff performance, assign tasks and salary sheets
- Used Java as core language with Eclipse RCP (Rich Client Platform): for frontend and backend and MYSQL as database system.
- Led transition to paperless practice by implementing electronic booking system and faster, safer and more accurate business system; reduced cost of labor by 30% and office overhead by 10%.
- Increased overall employee productivity by 25% by implementing effective task management and performance tracking systems, ensuring that goals are met and exceeded.
- Designed custom dashboards and automatic report generating weekly, monthly and annually.

Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, Java Script, React and MySQL

IT Trainer and Tutor, 07/2015 - 08/2018

Ministry Of Local Government – Asmara, Eritrea

- Taught 850+ staff employers in Southern Region of Eritrea, basic introductions in computer usage,
 Microsoft office packages, and computer maintenance and general foundation of computer world
- Worked as advisor and Help Desk for regional office.
- **Technologies Used**: Slack, MS Teams, WebEx, Zoom, Confluence, Windows, Mac, IOS, Team-Viewer, Antivirus Tools

Desktop Client and Server Side App Developer, 01/2014 - 01/2015

Eritrean Institution Technology Graduate Project / Asmara, Eritrea – Asmara, Eritrea

- As undergraduate final project, I, with help of 4 other group members, developed desktop application that helps 12th grade students select their ideal postsecondary education stream based on their grades and interests. Resulting total shifting from manual to computerized system by 100%
- Application was then used by Eritrean Ministry of Education as substitute for hardcopy and Microsoft Excel in recording and registering student information
- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JS, VB.NET, ASP.NET, elegant, WPF, Crystal Reports

• Project Name: Boundless Peace and Hope Intuitive

• Date Period: January 2023 - June 2023

• Location: Remote

• Short Summary of Work: Developed a comprehensive website for Refuge, a non-profit organization dedicated to providing support and resources for displaced individuals and refugees of the south sudan camp. Utilized React for the front end, styled components for styling design, Go for the backend, and MySQL for database management

• Successful Outcome: Raised \$7,500 for the charity through online donations and fundraising events facilitated by the website. Increased user engagement and outreach for the organization.

	Education -
Go Certificate: Go Programming, 01/2024	
Comit - Winnipeg, Manitoba	
Complete Web Development Boot camp: Full Stack Web Development, 01/2023 Udemy Online - Online	
Bachelor of Science: Computer Science, 07/2	2016
Eritrea Institution Technology - Asmara, Eritrea	
	- Awards -

- Best Project of the Year Award, Eritrean Institution Technology, 2015
- Certificate of Achievement in Android App Development